Muhammad Usman

Full Stack Developer

House No. 84 I-block Shah Rukne Alam Colony, Multan (+92) 337 6024922 usmangq12@gmail.com linkedin.com/muhammad-usman github.com/usmangq12 twitter.com/Muhammad-Usman

I'm a community-taught developer with 4 plus years of experience. I love reading and enhancing my knowledge daily, and I love solving complex problems. I'm really good at layouts, problem-solving, feature leading, learning, googling & figuring out the best approaches. I'm always ready for new challenges which keep me motivated to move on in the coding field at another level.

EXPERIENCE

SHARE Mobility, Columbus, United States

Senior Frontend Developer, Remote

September 2020 - PRESENT

- Helped craft the driving module for Ride-Hailing. Created booking rides, rate-ride, referral-reward.
- Built optimized routes system for admin panel using Google Maps API.
- Created auto-response back system based on AI using Twilio.

Geminus.AI, Palo Alto, California, United States

Frontend Developer, Remote

JULY 2019 - August 2020

- Supervised team of 3 developers engaged in Front-end development.
- Built dashboards to visualize Functional Gas Stations data. Created admin dashboard for municipal corporation system by developing alarm system using MQTT service.
- Created visuals to help identify leaks, pressure drops, and other potential problems.

Curiato, Canada

JavaScript Developer, Remote

October 2017 – June 2019

 Developed highly customized charts using D3 to visualize the clinicp'tient's clinical conditionseated interactive visuals on PowerBI to express different clinical metrics.

EDUCATION

University Of Education, Lahore Campus Multan – *BSIT*

[2014 - 2018]

Skills

- Languages (JavaScript, Typescript, Java)
- JavaScript Frameworks (React, Next.js, Vue)
- Databases (MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL)
- AWS Cloud serverless services
- Visualizations (D3.js, PowerBI)
- near-api-js
- Performance Optimization (SSR, Memoization)
- Git actions
- CSS frameworks (Bootstrap, Material, Ant design, Tailwind)
- Backend architecture (Express)

Personal Projects

Sensors-APP (React, Typescript, recharts, material-table, axios, Express, PostgreSQL)

Built a dashboard to display charts and tables against the real-time sensors collected data fetched by Sensors-API.

usmangq12/sensors-app

usmangq12/sensors-api

CURRENCY-CALCULATOR (React, styled-components, react-redux, redux-saga, react-table)

Created header with base currency (to be used on all the routes), the first component where base currency, target currency dropdowns, and amount field is shown to get desired results. The currency exchange grid is added to another component against the selected base currency header to see all its currency rates.

usmangq12/currency-converter

Activities

I love to play cricket on weekends. I always keep engaging myself in the community to learn more from others' experiences. I keep myself updated with new technologies and am motivated by reading books. Nowadays, I'm focused to learn web3.